Michael Wheatley

York 07564164177



mikewheatley@outlook.com



github.com/MoikeCheck



linkedin.com/in/michael-wheatley

INTRODUCTION

I'm currently working towards a career switch into Web & Software Development from my previous career in Insurance. Drawing motivation from an admiration of tech and awe of what coding can achieve. My customer service experience has left me with strong communication skills and a keen work ethic. I have collaborated on projects, networked with industry professionals and studied in my spare time to reach a point where I am at today with JavaScript, HTML and CSS. I have more recently graduated from a 12 week software bootcamp, Northcoders, which has given me solid foundations for my future learning. I am ready and excited for the next step in my new career to maintain momentum and continue developing, creating projects within a professional setting.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• Language

JAVASCRIPT

Front End

REACT | CSS3 | HTML5 | NODE JS

Back End

EXPRESS | SQL | NODE JS | RESTful API

• Test Driven Development

JEST | SUPERTEST

EXPERIENCE

Northcoders - Software Bootcamp - 2022 - Present

CODING FUNDAMENTALS | FRONT END | BACK END | GROUP PROJECT

Front End Project (1 week solo sprint) - For my front-end project I built a news site pulling data from an API and utilizing the React framework to create a seamless multi-page site with reusable componants.

github.com/MoikeCheck/nc-news // https://zestnews.netlify.app/

Back End Project (1 week solo sprint) - For this project I built a RESTful API that will connect to my Front End project enabling the data to be requested, added, modified and removed by the user.

github.com/MoikeCheck/be-NCnews // https://zestnews.herokuapp.com/api

Final Project (2 week team sprint) - For this final project my team and I were tasked with creating a full stack product. Our web app MVP is a platform where pet owners can locate pet services near them with a range of utilities such as reviews, ratings, messaging and mapping.

qithub.com/MoikeCheck/pet-app // pet-app-beta.vercel.app/

EMPLOYMENT

NFU Mutual, York - Senior Claims Handler/Customer Relationship Specialist

2016 - PRESENT

- Responsible for handling motor claims, making concise liability decisions based on relevant case law and dealing with claims that have reached a litigated stage.
- Supporting the department in the coaching and training of staff.
- Handling large losses or complex claims.

Minster Law, York - Personal Claims Advisor / Legal Assistant

2015 - 2016

- Responsible for capturing road traffic accidents accurately. Offering legal, repair and hire services to clients while also handling any complaints.
- The skills I had learnt as a claims advisor helped me progress onto becoming a legal assistant for their technical claims team where I aided my Fee Earner with litigated motorbike injury claims.

EDUCATION

Red Sky Learning - Aspiring Leader Program

2019-2020

Kaplan - Insurance Practitioner/Cert CII

2018 - 2020

York College - Creative Media Level 3 Extended Diploma (Equivalent to 3 A levels at grade B)

2010 - 2012

York College - Creative Media Level 2 Diploma (Equivalent to 4 GCSEs)

2009 - 2010

The Market Weighton School - 7 GCSEs at grade C or above.